JOE GILLS

(434) 607-7043 • josephgills@outlook.com

SUMMARY

Object oriented C++ software developer with experience taking projects from an idea to delivery. Outgoing and highly motivated with a passion for solving problems and improving processes. Over 4 years of experience developing C++ applications that integrate new technology and hardware components into larger systems.

TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES

- 4+ years: C/C++, Java, Git, Linux (RHEL & Ubuntu), C#, Google Test
- 2+ years: Python, Jenkins, Jira, Fortify Static Code Analyzer, HTML5, Doxygen, LCOV Code Coverage
- 1+ years: Artifactory, Wireshark

EXPERIENCE

Computer Scientist, Naval Surface Ware Center Dahlgren Division - Dahlgren, VA

June 2016 - Present

Summary: Work in an agile team to design, develop, test and maintain multiple C++ and Java software applications. Research new technologies and analyze software designs to anticipate issues and resolve problems early.

Technical Accomplishments:

- Debug, maintain and test C++ and Java GUI applications running in a RHEL environment that configure and control GPS Sensors, Omni Directional and RF tracking antennas over UDP and TCP interfaces.
- Develop and maintain software documentation and user manuals for various C++ services and Java GUI
 applications.
- Develop unit tests using the google test framework for C++ applications that test public interfaces of utility classes.
- Worked directly with end users from a wide range of backgrounds to understand engineering and technical issues encountered in combat. Worked in a small team to prototype, test and deploy solutions with a guick turnaround.
- Improved system performance by analyzing network traffic with custom Python scripts and implemented enhancements.
- Integrated a RF tracking antenna into a tactical control system using a C++ daemon service. The multithreaded application configures, controls and monitors the status of the hardware.
- Improved code quality by installing and configuring a Jenkins server to automate unit testing, code coverage reports, Doxygen documentation generation, RPM builds, build status and Fortify Static Code Analyzers into a DevOps pipeline.
- Introduced pull requests and code review technologies into software processes.
- Designed and developed a multithreaded application in C++/CUDA that leveraged multiple high performance GPUs that implemented several noise filtering algorithms for a detection and tracking system.

Software Engineer, MVM, Inc. - Farmville, VA

June 2015 – June 2016

• Led system engineering discussions with senior leadership to gather system requirements for a MVC ASP.NET web application. Developed and conducted usability test with end-users to test applications and collect feedback. Primary developer for several ASP.NET MVC web applications.

EDUCATION

M.S. Degree in Computer Science, Old Dominion University

Jan 2017 - Present

GPA: 3.95; Expected Graduation: Dec. 2021

B.S. Degree in Mathematics & Computer Science, Longwood University

August 2011 - May 2015

GPA: 3.78; Summa Cum Laude; Cum Honore; Cormier Honors College; PRISM Research

AWARDS & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

NSWCDD A40 Peer Recognition Award – 1st QTR FY17 Awardee

2017

Special Achievement category winner for the development of the Adjunct Maritime Processor.

Badger-Magnifico Award – Longwood University Math & Computer Science Department

2015

"This award honors the highest achievement for graduating seniors both in the department and at Longwood overall."